<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-10-05T14:21:54-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Global Carbon Footprint</title><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Global-Carbon-Footprint/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Global Carbon Footprint"/><published>2023-10-05T12:40:16-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T12:40:16-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Global-Carbon-Footprint</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Global-Carbon-Footprint/"><![CDATA[<p>The global carbon footprint is a crucial metric that measures the total amount of greenhouse gases, primarily carbon dioxide (CO2), emitted into the Earth’s atmosphere as a result of human activities. These activities include burning fossil fuels for energy, deforestation, industrial processes, and various agricultural practices. The concept of a carbon footprint is instrumental in assessing humanity’s impact on climate change and understanding the level of responsibility each country, industry, and individual bears in contributing to this global issue.</p> <p>Several key points are essential to consider when discussing the global carbon footprint:</p> <p>Contributing Factors: The major contributors to the global carbon footprint are the burning of fossil fuels for energy production and transportation. These activities release vast quantities of CO2 into the atmosphere. Additionally, deforestation, which reduces the Earth’s capacity to absorb CO2, also plays a significant role.</p> <p>Regional Disparities: There are substantial regional disparities in carbon footprints. Developed countries tend to have higher per capita emissions due to their greater energy consumption and industrial activities, while developing countries often have lower per capita emissions but are experiencing rapid increases as they industrialize and urbanize.</p> <p>Industrial and Agricultural Practices: Industries like manufacturing, cement production, and agriculture release significant amounts of greenhouse gases, such as methane (CH4) and nitrous oxide (N2O), in addition to CO2. These gases are potent contributors to the carbon footprint.</p> <p>Renewable Energy and Mitigation: Transitioning to renewable energy sources like wind, solar, and hydropower can significantly reduce carbon footprints. Additionally, carbon capture and storage (CCS) technologies and afforestation (planting trees) are mitigation strategies aimed at reducing atmospheric CO2 levels.</p> <p>International Agreements: Global efforts to address the carbon footprint include international agreements like the Paris Agreement, which aims to limit global warming to well below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels. Countries that are parties to this agreement have pledged to reduce their carbon emissions.</p> <p>Individual Responsibility: Individuals also play a role in reducing the carbon footprint through lifestyle choices such as reducing energy consumption, using public transportation, adopting sustainable agricultural practices, and minimizing waste.</p> <p>Climate Impact: The global carbon footprint has a direct impact on climate change, contributing to rising global temperatures, sea-level rise, extreme weather events, and disruptions to ecosystems. These effects have far-reaching consequences on human societies and the planet’s biodiversity.</p> <p>Monitoring and reducing the global carbon footprint is critical for mitigating the worst impacts of climate change. It requires international cooperation, technological innovation, policy changes, and individual efforts to transition to a more sustainable and low-carbon future. Achieving a sustainable balance between human activities and the health of our planet is one of the most pressing challenges of the 21st century.</p> <p>Here is the map of global carbon footprint. Among the countries, China is major contributor to Co2 emission.</p> <iframe width="1000" height="1000" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://wagle1996.github.io/carbon-footprint/"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Information"/><category term="Web_map"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global Carbon Footprint]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Private School in US</title><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Private-schools-in-US/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Private School in US"/><published>2023-10-04T12:40:16-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-04T12:40:16-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Private-schools-in-US</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Private-schools-in-US/"><![CDATA[<p>This web map shows the information of private school in US.</p> <iframe width="1000" height="1000" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://wagle1996.github.io/Private_Schools_US_webmap/#4/-16.47/-11.29"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Information"/><category term="Web_map"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information of Private School in US]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Visiting India Point Park</title><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Story-Map/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Visiting India Point Park"/><published>2023-09-28T13:39:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-28T13:39:00-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Story-Map</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Story-Map/"><![CDATA[<p>Redirecting to another page.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Places_to_visit"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring beutiful place of RI]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rhode Island Hospitals</title><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Hospital-info-of-Rhode-Island/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rhode Island Hospitals"/><published>2023-09-24T12:40:16-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-24T12:40:16-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Hospital-info-of-Rhode-Island</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Hospital-info-of-Rhode-Island/"><![CDATA[<p>There are many hospitals in rhode island. This dashboard was created using ArcGIS dashboard and webmap is created using ArcGIS online.</p> <iframe width="1000" height="1000" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://brown.maps.arcgis.com/apps/dashboards/c3242870cae54d1d950e9bf5683a4110"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Information"/><category term="Dashboards"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information of Hospitals in Rhode Island (Dashboard)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rhode Island’s Hidden Treasures</title><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Places-to-visit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rhode Island’s Hidden Treasures"/><published>2023-08-07T03:33:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T03:33:00-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Places-to-visit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2023/Places-to-visit/"><![CDATA[<p>Best Places to visit in rhode island</p> <h2 id="top-places-to-visit">Top places to visit</h2> <div class="language-yml highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="s">1. Marble house</span>
<span class="s">2. Waterfire Providence</span>
<span class="s">3. Blitheworld Mansion</span>
<span class="s">4. Brenton Point State Park</span>
<span class="s">5. Colt State Park</span>
<span class="s">6. Breakers</span>
<span class="s">7. Roger Williams Park zoo</span>
<span class="s">8. ROger Williams Memorial park</span>
<span class="s">9. RISD Museum</span> 
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Introduction</p> <p>Rhode Island, the smallest state in the U.S., is a land of hidden gems waiting to be discovered. From opulent mansions to tranquil parks and cultural havens, the Ocean State has it all. In this blog post, we’ll take you on a journey through nine must-visit places that showcase the rich history, natural beauty, and cultural vibrancy of Rhode Island.</p> <p>Marble House - A Gilded Age Extravaganza</p> <p>Marble House, a masterpiece of architectural opulence, is a testament to the Gilded Age’s extravagance. Built by William K. Vanderbilt, it features stunning marble facades and luxurious interiors. Step back in time as you explore the lavish rooms and beautiful gardens overlooking the Atlantic Ocean.</p> <p>WaterFire Providence - An Enchanting Spectacle</p> <p>WaterFire Providence is a mesmerizing art installation that transforms the city’s rivers into a breathtaking display of fire and light. The sight of dozens of bonfires set ablaze on the water’s surface against a backdrop of live music and local artwork is truly enchanting.</p> <p>Blithewold Mansion - A Garden Lover’s Paradise</p> <p>Blithewold Mansion and Arboretum is a horticultural delight. Stroll through its beautifully landscaped gardens, which come alive with vibrant blooms in the spring and summer. The mansion itself is a step back in time, offering a glimpse into the lives of the wealthy Van Wickle family.</p> <p>Brenton Point State Park - Coastal Beauty Unveiled</p> <p>For panoramic views of the Rhode Island coastline, Brenton Point State Park is the place to be. Located on the Ocean Drive in Newport, it’s a serene spot for picnics, kite flying, and enjoying the fresh sea breeze.</p> <p>Colt State Park - Nature’s Haven</p> <p>Colt State Park is a nature lover’s paradise. With its vast lawns, meandering bike paths, and scenic views of Narragansett Bay, it’s perfect for hiking, birdwatching, or simply unwinding in a tranquil environment.</p> <p>The Breakers - A Symbol of Luxury</p> <p>The Breakers, a symbol of Newport’s historic wealth, is another must-see mansion. Its grandeur and elegance, set against the backdrop of the Atlantic Ocean, are awe-inspiring. Explore the mansion’s opulent rooms and beautifully manicured gardens.</p> <p>Roger Williams Park Zoo - Family Fun</p> <p>Roger Williams Park Zoo is an educational and entertaining destination for families. Home to a diverse array of animals from around the world, it offers opportunities for both learning and close encounters with wildlife.</p> <p>Roger Williams Memorial Park - A Green Oasis</p> <p>Roger Williams Memorial Park is a serene green oasis in the heart of Providence. It’s the perfect place for a leisurely stroll, a peaceful picnic, or simply to enjoy the tranquility of nature in the midst of the city.</p> <p>RISD Museum - A Cultural Gem</p> <p>The RISD Museum, affiliated with the Rhode Island School of Design, houses an impressive collection of art and artifacts from around the world. Explore its galleries to discover an eclectic mix of contemporary and historical works, making it a must-visit for art enthusiasts.</p> <p>Conclusion</p> <p>Rhode Island may be the nation’s smallest state, but it’s brimming with cultural treasures, natural beauty, and historic charm. These nine must-visit places in Rhode Island offer a glimpse into the state’s rich history, vibrant culture, and stunning landscapes. Whether you’re a history buff, nature lover, or art enthusiast, Rhode Island has something special to offer you. So, pack your bags and embark on a journey to uncover the hidden treasures of the Ocean State. These are the most important places to visit in Rhode Island and are my top choices.</p> <p>See the Map below for the places you need to visit in Rhode Island. click the placemark to see details of the places.</p> <iframe width="1000" height="1000" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://wagle1996.github.io/Places_to_visit_webmap/#10/41.6421/-71.3562"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Information"/><category term="Places_to_visit"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best places where I have visited in Rhode Island]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T19:20:09-04:00</updated><id>https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wagle1996.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>